Clinton Judy

State College, PA, USA 8145315839 clinton@judy.io http://judy.github.io

I'm a web developer living in State College, Pennsylvania. I've been programming my entire life, and a Rails developer for the last 8 years. I love the practice of software craftsmanship, and I strive to amaze every client I work with. I am actively looking for a full-time web development, developer operations, or team management position.

Technical Skills

Likes:

ruby-on-rails, html5, coffeescript, postgresql, redis, reactjs, d3.js

Experience

Senior Rails Engineer-Agrian, Inc.

November 2013 - January 2016

ruby, rails, postgresql, postgis, html5, css3, rabbitmq, redis, open-source, bigdata

- Designed and implemented several major service-oriented applications for the precision agriculture industry.
- Devised programming strategies for handling wide variety of raw file data formats.
- Optimized code for handling big data problems (100 million rows per month).
- Rewrote legacy code to distribute work and reduce load (100s of workers, 100,000s of jobs daily).

Open Source Lead - Fractured Atlas

May 2012 - October 2013

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, mysql, haml, user-experience, rails-engines, open-source, angularjs

- Worked on Artful.ly, a system for managing customers and selling tickets online.
- Turned the majority of Artful.ly into an open source Rails engine for use by other organizations.
- Developed a discount system for promoters and customers when selling and buying tickets.
- Developed advanced searching and list segment features for organizing customer lists.
- Overhauled the sign up and sign-in flows for Artful.ly, increasing conversion rates.

Contract Web Developer-Copious

February 2012 - April 2012

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, rspec, redis, mysql, postgresql

- Worked on VIE Sports, a social networking site for athletes.
- Created the achievement system, rewarding users for actions taken throughout the site.
- Developed the "wall", a feed of your comments, competitions entered, scores, friendships made, and even more.
- Developed privacy controls, so you get to control which people get to see which things you've done.
- Cleaned up a large amount of outdated and broken tests, so we were able to deliver a codebase with 100% of tests
 passing and nearly complete code coverage to the client.
- Designed other parts of the UI, including score entry and location search.

Web Developer - West Arete Computing

February 2009 – October 2011

ruby, rails, html, css, coffeescript, javascript

- Estimated, designed, developed, and launched websites out of several experimental technologies and ideas with MIT, Penn State, the DOT, and the Marine Biological Laboratory.
- · Project lead on websites for several high-profile companies in Centre County.
- Represented the company at networking events.
- · Assisted the hiring process for new employees.
- Respected for my opinion with the direction of the company.

Web Developer-CWS Web Services powershell, ruby, rails

November 2008 – January 2009

- Developed a tool to manage virtual machines and application sequencing
- Installed, configured, networked, and supported hardware for local businesses, including a 40+ thin-client installation at a free health clinic.

ruby, rails, flex, asp.net, html, css

- Developed applications to assist with company roles, including resume management and production scheduling.
- Created and maintained the company intranet.
- Updated the <u>public website</u>.
- Repaired and installed computers and networking equipment at various remote locations throughout Pennsylvania and New York, including an airport control tower.

Graphic Designer-Menu Master

February 2007 - May 2007

illustrator, photoshop, indesign

- Designed eye-catching menus, place-mats and takeout menus.
- Communicated with 14-20 listed advertisers per project to ensure each advertiser was happy with the layout of their completed design.
- Collaborated with the company's print shop for project receiving and proper color matching.

Web Developer, Graphic Designer - Freelance

October 2004 - February 2007

adobe-illustrator, html, css, photoshop

Designed a variety of graphic and web designs for local businesses and non-profit organizations, including a
newspaper flyer for a muzzleloader supply store, a menu for a local diner, websites for student organizations, and
wall flyers for student-run events.

Education

Graphic and Online Design, Computer Science—Lock Haven University of Pennsylvania c, c++, compilers, oop, graphic-design, fine-arts

2004 - 2007

- Fine Arts Society 2 years
- Ultimate Team 2 years
- Improv Team 3 years
- · Cantori (Choir) 3 years

Projects & Interests

GitHub - Kanina – https://github.com/judy/kanina ruby, rabbitmq

February 2015

A Rails plugin for easily sending and receiving messages with RabbitMQ.

I wrote this library from scratch to simplify message sending/receiving, from Rails to RabbitMQ. It's currently being used in a production environment, handling thousands of messages daily.

GitHub - Artfully OSE - https://github.com/judy/artfully_ose

February 2013

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript

Open-source Rails engine to help you sell tickets, take donations, and track fans.

I was the open source lead on this project.

GitHub - karma-server - https://github.com/judy/karma-server

February 2012

ruby, ruby-on-rails, cucumber, rspec, html5, css3

A RESTful API for tracking "karma" points of users across several separate websites.

I was a primary developer on this project.

GitHub - Lifeviz - https://github.com/judy/Lifeviz

February 2012

ruby, ruby-on-rails, cucumber, rspec, html5, css3, protovis

A macroscope, that expands your field of view across the tree of life and enables you to find trends in longevity data.

I was the project lead and primary developer on this project.

VIE Sports for iPhone 3GS, iPhone 4, iPhone 4S, iPod touch (3rd generation), iPod touch (4th generation) and iPad – http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vie-sports/id502147014?mt=8

objective-c, ruby-on-rails, rspec

Compete against your friends virtually, using your own real-life stats and scores.

I developed new functionality for the website to match existing functionality on the iPhone app. I also helped create the APIs for some of the major features on the iPhone app.